chapter one
Once when I was six years old I saw a
magnificent picture in a book, called
True Stories from Nature, about the
primeval forest
the forest which has never been cut down
and felt an ax
It was a picture of a boa constrictor in
the act of swallowing an animal.
Here is a copy of the drawing.
In the book it said:
"Boa constrictors swallow their prey hole
without chewing After that they are not
able to move, and they sleep for six
months to digest the meal
I then Ponder deeply over the adventures
in the jungle.
And after some work with a colored
pencil I succeeded in making my first
drawing.
My Drawing Number One was like this:
I showed my masterpiece to the grown-ups,
and asked them whether my drawing
frightened them.
But they answered
frightened
Why should anyone be frightened by a hat?"
My drawing was not a picture of a hat.
It was a picture of a boa constrictor
digesting an elephant.
But since the grown-ups were not able to
understand it, I made another drawing:
I now drew the inside of the boa
constrictor the grown-ups always need to
have things explained to them
My new Drawing showing the elephant
inside the boa constrictor looked like
this:
The grown-ups' response, this time,
was to advise me to lay aside my
drawings of boa constrictors, whether
from the inside or the outside, and to
devote myself instead to geography,
history, arithmetic and grammar.
That is why, at the age of six, I gave up
a magnificent career as a painter.
I had been disheartened by the failure
of my Drawing Number One and my Drawing
Number Two.
Grown-ups never understand anything by
themselves, and it is tiresome for
children to always explain things to
them.
So then I chose another profession,
and I learned to pilot airplanes
but I have flown almost over the world;
and this is true that geography has been
very useful to me I can At a glance
distinguish between China and Arizona.
If one gets lost in the night, such
knowledge is valuable
throughout my life I've been in touch
with many kinds of serious people
I have lived a great deal with grown-ups
I've seen them intimately,
close at hand.
And that I'm afraid hasn't much improved
my opinion of them.
Whenever I met one of them who seemed to
me at all clear-sighted,
I tried the experiment of showing him my
Drawing Number One, which I always kept
at hand
I'll try to find out whether the person
was truly understanding.
But the answer was always
That is a hat."
Then I would never talk to that person
about boa constrictors, or primeval
forests, or stars
I'd bring myself down to his level and
talk about bridge golf politics, and
neckties.
And the grown-up would be greatly
pleased to have met such a sensible
person